<br />
<b>Warning</b>:  Undefined array key "use-forms" in <b>C:\laragon\www\swallow-training\wp-content\plugins\simply-static-pro\src\form\class-ssp-form-settings.php</b> on line <b>42</b><br />
<br />
<b>Warning</b>:  Undefined array key "use-forms" in <b>C:\laragon\www\swallow-training\wp-content\plugins\simply-static-pro\src\form\class-ssp-form-webhook.php</b> on line <b>39</b><br />
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Pelatihan Walet</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>The Best Swallow Cultivation Seminar and Training Provider in Indonesia</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 08:17:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/cropped-icon-training-walet-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Pelatihan Walet</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to Solve Problems in Swallows: Common Diseases and Disorders that Often Occur</title>
		<link>/how-to-solve-problems-in-swallows-common-diseases-and-disorders-that-often-occur</link>
					<comments>/how-to-solve-problems-in-swallows-common-diseases-and-disorders-that-often-occur#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[raulilma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 07:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Burung Walet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tutorial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trainingwalet.test/?p=811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Swiftlet is a very valuable livestock animal because it produces swallow nests, which are used as raw materials in the food and cosmetic industries. However, swiftlets are also susceptible to various diseases and disorders, which can disrupt the production of swiftlet nests and threaten the health of birds. Therefore, it is important for swiftlet breeders &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/how-to-solve-problems-in-swallows-common-diseases-and-disorders-that-often-occur"> <span class="screen-reader-text">How to Solve Problems in Swallows: Common Diseases and Disorders that Often Occur</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="811" class="elementor elementor-811">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-743e694d elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="743e694d" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6f6103ca" data-id="6f6103ca" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-55dbeb3d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="55dbeb3d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<style>/*! elementor - v3.11.2 - 22-02-2023 */
.elementor-widget-text-editor.elementor-drop-cap-view-stacked .elementor-drop-cap{background-color:#818a91;color:#fff}.elementor-widget-text-editor.elementor-drop-cap-view-framed .elementor-drop-cap{color:#818a91;border:3px solid;background-color:transparent}.elementor-widget-text-editor:not(.elementor-drop-cap-view-default) .elementor-drop-cap{margin-top:8px}.elementor-widget-text-editor:not(.elementor-drop-cap-view-default) .elementor-drop-cap-letter{width:1em;height:1em}.elementor-widget-text-editor .elementor-drop-cap{float:left;text-align:center;line-height:1;font-size:50px}.elementor-widget-text-editor .elementor-drop-cap-letter{display:inline-block}</style>				<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<div class="w-full border-b border-black/10 dark:border-gray-900/50 text-gray-800 dark:text-gray-100 group bg-gray-50 dark:bg-[#444654]">
<div class="text-base gap-4 md:gap-6 m-auto md:max-w-2xl lg:max-w-2xl xl:max-w-3xl p-4 md:py-6 flex lg:px-0">
<div class="relative flex w-[calc(100%-50px)] flex-col gap-1 md:gap-3 lg:w-[calc(100%-115px)]">
<div class="flex flex-grow flex-col gap-3">
<div class="min-h-[20px] flex flex-col items-start gap-4 whitespace-pre-wrap">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<div class="w-full border-b border-black/10 dark:border-gray-900/50 text-gray-800 dark:text-gray-100 group bg-gray-50 dark:bg-[#444654]">
<div class="text-base gap-4 md:gap-6 m-auto md:max-w-2xl lg:max-w-2xl xl:max-w-3xl p-4 md:py-6 flex lg:px-0">
<div class="relative flex w-[calc(100%-50px)] flex-col gap-1 md:gap-3 lg:w-[calc(100%-115px)]">
<div class="flex flex-grow flex-col gap-3">
<div class="min-h-[20px] flex flex-col items-start gap-4 whitespace-pre-wrap">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<p>Swiftlet is a very valuable livestock animal because it produces swallow nests, which are used as raw materials in the food and cosmetic industries. However, swiftlets are also susceptible to various diseases and disorders, which can disrupt the production of swiftlet nests and threaten the health of birds. Therefore, it is important for swiftlet breeders to know how to deal with problems that often occur in swiftlets. Here are some common problems with swallows and how to deal with them:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Respiratory Disease</strong>: Respiratory disease in swallows can be caused by various factors, such as viruses, bacteria, fungi, or parasites. Common symptoms of respiratory disease in swiftlets are shortness of breath, coughing, sneezing and excessive mucus production. To treat respiratory diseases, you can give antibiotics and anti-inflammatory drugs to swallows. In addition, ensure the cleanliness of the cage and adequate ventilation to avoid spreading disease.</li>
<li><strong>Respiratory Disorders</strong>: Respiratory disorders in swallows can be caused by air that is too humid, dust, or smoke. Common symptoms of respiratory problems in swallows are shortness of breath and coughing. To treat respiratory problems, ensure adequate ventilation of the cage and avoid using harmful chemicals or cleaning products.</li>
<li><strong>Nail and Finger Disease</strong>: Nail and finger disease in swiftlets can be caused by bacterial or fungal infections, or by nutritional deficiencies. Common symptoms of finger and nail disease in swiftlets are changes in the color or shape of the nails, pain when walking or moving, and swelling. To treat nail and finger disease, ensure the cleanliness of the cage and provide a balanced diet with adequate nutrition.</li>
<li><strong>Stress</strong>: Stress in swallows can be caused by a variety of factors, such as an unsuitable environment, a lack of food and water, or the presence of predators. Common symptoms of stress on swallows are decreased production of swiftlet nests, loss of feathers, and changes in behavior. To deal with stress, make sure the cage conditions are comfortable and safe, and provide enough food and water.</li>
<li><strong>Reproductive Disorders</strong>: Reproductive disorders in swallows can affect nest production, so they need to be taken seriously. Some of the reproductive disorders that often occur in swallows include:
<ol>
<li>Eggs Not Hatching: Unhatched eggs can be caused by several factors such as unfertilized eggs, immature eggs, or diseases that attack the eggs. If this happens, it is best to immediately dispose of the unhatched eggs to prevent infection of the nest.</li>
<li>Broken egg: Cracked eggs can occur due to several factors such as unstable temperatures, rough treatment of the nest, or humidity that is too high. If this happens, immediately clean the nest and replace the broken eggs with new eggs.</li>
<li>Birds Don&#8217;t Lay Eggs: If birds don&#8217;t lay eggs for a long time, several factors need to be considered, such as lack of nutrition, old birds, or unfavorable environmental conditions. It&#8217;s best to take good care of swallows, such as providing a balanced diet, keeping the nest clean, and providing a comfortable environment.</li>
<li>Unhealthy Eggs: Unhealthy eggs can be caused by several factors such as diseased birds, unbalanced nutrition, or unsupportive environmental conditions. If the eggs produced by swiftlets are unhealthy, these eggs should not be consumed or sold, because they can endanger the health of consumers.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p>Caring for swallows does require serious attention, including dealing with possible problems such as disease and reproductive disorders. As the owner of a swallow&#8217;s nest, it is important to always monitor the health of birds and nests, provide a balanced diet, and maintain the cleanliness of the environment around the nest. Thus, the production of swallow nests can be maintained properly and provide optimal benefits.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/how-to-solve-problems-in-swallows-common-diseases-and-disorders-that-often-occur/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Platform Pelatihan Walet: Costs, Availability, and Training Materials.</title>
		<link>/platform-pelatihan-walet-costs-availability-and-training-materials</link>
					<comments>/platform-pelatihan-walet-costs-availability-and-training-materials#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[raulilma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 06:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Burung Walet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trainingwalet.test/?p=789</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pelatihan Walet is becoming increasingly popular among swiftlet entrepreneurs as it helps them improve their production results and the quality of swiftlet nests. However, not everyone is aware of the costs, availability, and training materials offered by swiftlet training providers. Here is complete information that can help you better understand Pelatihan Walet. Cost of Pelatihan &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/platform-pelatihan-walet-costs-availability-and-training-materials"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Platform Pelatihan Walet: Costs, Availability, and Training Materials.</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="789" class="elementor elementor-789">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-743e694d elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="743e694d" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6f6103ca" data-id="6f6103ca" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-55dbeb3d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="55dbeb3d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<div class="w-full border-b border-black/10 dark:border-gray-900/50 text-gray-800 dark:text-gray-100 group bg-gray-50 dark:bg-[#444654]">
<div class="text-base gap-4 md:gap-6 m-auto md:max-w-2xl lg:max-w-2xl xl:max-w-3xl p-4 md:py-6 flex lg:px-0">
<div class="relative flex w-[calc(100%-50px)] flex-col gap-1 md:gap-3 lg:w-[calc(100%-115px)]">
<div class="flex flex-grow flex-col gap-3">
<div class="min-h-[20px] flex flex-col items-start gap-4 whitespace-pre-wrap">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<div class="w-full border-b border-black/10 dark:border-gray-900/50 text-gray-800 dark:text-gray-100 group bg-gray-50 dark:bg-[#444654]">
<div class="text-base gap-4 md:gap-6 m-auto md:max-w-2xl lg:max-w-2xl xl:max-w-3xl p-4 md:py-6 flex lg:px-0">
<div class="relative flex w-[calc(100%-50px)] flex-col gap-1 md:gap-3 lg:w-[calc(100%-115px)]">
<div class="flex flex-grow flex-col gap-3">
<div class="min-h-[20px] flex flex-col items-start gap-4 whitespace-pre-wrap">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<p>Pelatihan Walet is becoming increasingly popular among swiftlet entrepreneurs as it helps them improve their production results and the quality of swiftlet nests. However, not everyone is aware of the costs, availability, and training materials offered by swiftlet training providers. Here is complete information that can help you better understand Pelatihan Walet.</p>
<p><strong>Cost of Pelatihan Walet</strong></p>
<p>The cost of Pelatihan Walet varies depending on the type of training and training provider. There are several swiftlet training providers in Indonesia that offer various types of training, such as cultivation training, nest management, and nest processing. The cost of training ranges from several hundred thousand to several million rupiahs.</p>
<p>In addition to the cost of training, you should also consider the cost of the platform used. One of the popular swiftlet training platforms is the Pelatihan Walet Platform. The subscription cost for the Pelatihan Walet Platform depends on the package you choose, ranging from several hundred thousand to several million rupiahs per month.</p>
<p><strong>Available in Which Cities</strong></p>
<p>Pelatihan Walet is available in many cities in Indonesia, such as Jakarta, Bandung, Surabaya, Yogyakarta, and Bali. However, with the existence of swiftlet training platforms such as Pelatihan Walet, you can access training from anywhere as long as you have a stable internet connection.</p>
<p><strong>What&#8217;s Available in the Training</strong></p>
<p>Pelatihan Walet usually consists of several sessions or modules that cover various aspects of breeding, management, and processing of swiftlet nests. Some of the topics that are often covered in swiftlet training include:</p>
<p>Planning and managing swiftlet breeding Care and management of swiftlet nests Selection and placement of swiftlet birdhouses Selection of swiftlet species for breeding Processing of swiftlet nests Introduction to technology in swiftlet breeding</p>
<p><strong>Advantages of the Pelatihan Walet Platform</strong></p>
<p>Pelatihan Walet is a swiftlet training platform that allows swiftlet entrepreneurs to access training from anywhere and anytime. Some of the advantages of Pelatihan Walet include:</p>
<p>Complete and structured training materials Learning that can be tailored to your needs Various training packages available at affordable prices Accessible from anywhere and anytime Supported by experienced swiftlet experts</p>
<p>In conclusion, Pelatihan Walet is a very useful training platform for aspiring swiftlet entrepreneurs who want to start their own business. The training provided by this platform is very complete, ranging from breeding techniques for swiftlet birds, building techniques for swiftlet birdhouses, harvesting techniques for swiftlet nests to marketing techniques for swiftlet nests. Affordable training costs and availability of training in various cities in Indonesia make the Pelatihan Walet platform a suitable choice for improving knowledge and skills in the swiftlet business.</p>
<p>In addition, another advantage of this platform is the availability of up-to-date training materials that can be accessed online anytime and anywhere. This makes it easier for participants to learn without having to come to the training location. Participants will also receive a certificate after completing the training, which can be an added value in finding investors or business partners.</p>
<p>Therefore, for aspiring swiftlet entrepreneurs who want to start their business, the Pelatihan Walet platform is highly recommended. With affordable costs, complete training, and ease of accessing training materials online, this platform will help improve knowledge and skills in the swiftlet business, thus helping to achieve success in the business.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/platform-pelatihan-walet-costs-availability-and-training-materials/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tips for Successful Harvesting of Bird&#8217;s Nest: Best Time, Bird&#8217;s Age, and Export Market</title>
		<link>/tips-for-successful-harvesting-of-birds-nest-best-time-birds-age-and-export-market</link>
					<comments>/tips-for-successful-harvesting-of-birds-nest-best-time-birds-age-and-export-market#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[raulilma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 04:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Burung Walet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trainingwalet.test/?p=779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Running a business in the swiftlet industry requires serious attention, especially in determining the right time for harvesting. The timing for harvesting is crucial as it affects the quality of the produced nests and the yield obtained. There are several factors to consider in determining the right harvesting time, including room temperature, weather conditions, nest &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/tips-for-successful-harvesting-of-birds-nest-best-time-birds-age-and-export-market"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Tips for Successful Harvesting of Bird&#8217;s Nest: Best Time, Bird&#8217;s Age, and Export Market</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="779" class="elementor elementor-779">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-743e694d elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="743e694d" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6f6103ca" data-id="6f6103ca" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-55dbeb3d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="55dbeb3d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<div class="w-full border-b border-black/10 dark:border-gray-900/50 text-gray-800 dark:text-gray-100 group bg-gray-50 dark:bg-[#444654]">
<div class="text-base gap-4 md:gap-6 m-auto md:max-w-2xl lg:max-w-2xl xl:max-w-3xl p-4 md:py-6 flex lg:px-0">
<div class="relative flex w-[calc(100%-50px)] flex-col gap-1 md:gap-3 lg:w-[calc(100%-115px)]">
<div class="flex flex-grow flex-col gap-3">
<div class="min-h-[20px] flex flex-col items-start gap-4 whitespace-pre-wrap">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<div class="w-full border-b border-black/10 dark:border-gray-900/50 text-gray-800 dark:text-gray-100 group bg-gray-50 dark:bg-[#444654]">
<div class="text-base gap-4 md:gap-6 m-auto md:max-w-2xl lg:max-w-2xl xl:max-w-3xl p-4 md:py-6 flex lg:px-0">
<div class="relative flex w-[calc(100%-50px)] flex-col gap-1 md:gap-3 lg:w-[calc(100%-115px)]">
<div class="flex flex-grow flex-col gap-3">
<div class="min-h-[20px] flex flex-col items-start gap-4 whitespace-pre-wrap">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<p>Running a business in the swiftlet industry requires serious attention, especially in determining the right time for harvesting. The timing for harvesting is crucial as it affects the quality of the produced nests and the yield obtained. There are several factors to consider in determining the right harvesting time, including room temperature, weather conditions, nest conditions, and the number of birds being raised.</p>
<p>According to successful swiftlet breeders, the best time for harvesting is in the morning around 5 to 8 a.m. At that time, the air temperature is still cool, and the nest conditions are not too dry. In addition, swiftlet birds have flown out to search for food in the morning, so they do not disturb the harvesting process. However, each breeder has different experiences in determining the right harvesting time according to their environmental and coop conditions.</p>
<p><strong>Best Time for Harvesting Swiftlet Nests</strong></p>
<p>Harvesting swiftlet nests should be done at the right time to ensure maximum quality and quantity of the yield. Some experts suggest that harvesting should be done in the morning or late afternoon when swiftlet birds are still active and routinely entering and exiting the grotto. In addition, weather conditions also need to be considered. Do not harvest during bad weather such as rain or strong winds, as it can disturb the environmental balance in the grotto and affect the quality of the produced nests.</p>
<p><strong>Age of Swiftlet Birds and Their Life Cycle</strong></p>
<p>Knowing the age of swiftlet birds is important in running a swiftlet business. Swiftlet birds usually reach peak productivity at the age of 3 to 4 years. After reaching that age, the production of swiftlet nests will start to decline. Therefore, adding the swiftlet bird population is necessary to maintain the productivity of the produced nests.</p>
<p>The life cycle of swiftlet birds is divided into several phases, namely development, reproduction, growth, and rest phases. Each phase has different nutritional needs. Therefore, swiftlet business owners need to understand the life cycle phases of swiftlet birds to provide the right feed and nutrition according to the needs of the birds in each phase.</p>
<p><strong>Export Market for Swiftlet Nests</strong></p>
<p>Swiftlet nests are an export product with high demand in the international market, especially in East Asia such as China, Hong Kong, and Taiwan. In addition, countries such as the United States, Europe, and Australia are also potential markets for swiftlet nest products. Business operators can sell swiftlet nests directly abroad or through intermediaries or export agents. However, before starting exports, it is necessary to understand the regulations and export requirements in the destination country and conduct quality checks and required production standards.</p>
<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p>After learning about the swiftlet industry, we can conclude that swiftlet business can be a profitable opportunity with affordable capital. However, to achieve optimal results, several important factors need to be considered, such as the right harvesting time, good swiftlet bird maintenance, and the selection of the correct swiftlet nest processing method.</p>
<p>In addition, we also need to pay attention to regulations and halal certification to ensure that the produced swiftlet nests are acceptable in the global market and meet the needs of consumers who are increasingly aware of the quality of halal and safe products.</p>
<p>To further explore the swiftlet industry, there is a Training Walet platform that can provide training and guidance on swiftlet bird maintenance, swiftlet nest processing, and comprehensive swiftlet business development. By obtaining deeper knowledge about the swiftlet industry, we can increase the chance of success in running a promising business in this industry.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/tips-for-successful-harvesting-of-birds-nest-best-time-birds-age-and-export-market/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here are the Shocking Facts about Swallows that You Need to Know! What They Like to Eat, Why They are Expensive and Much More!</title>
		<link>/here-are-the-shocking-facts-about-swallows-that-you-need-to-know-what-they-like-to-eat-why-they-are-expensive-and-much-more</link>
					<comments>/here-are-the-shocking-facts-about-swallows-that-you-need-to-know-what-they-like-to-eat-why-they-are-expensive-and-much-more#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[raulilma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 04:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Burung Walet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trainingwalet.test/?p=761</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The swiftlet is a small bird known for its valuable nests that are used in the luxury food and beverage industry. However, despite the well-known economic value of swiftlet nests, there is still much to learn about the bird itself. For example, what do swiftlets like to eat and why is their saliva so expensive? &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/here-are-the-shocking-facts-about-swallows-that-you-need-to-know-what-they-like-to-eat-why-they-are-expensive-and-much-more"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Here are the Shocking Facts about Swallows that You Need to Know! What They Like to Eat, Why They are Expensive and Much More!</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="761" class="elementor elementor-761">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-743e694d elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="743e694d" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6f6103ca" data-id="6f6103ca" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-55dbeb3d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="55dbeb3d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<div class="group w-full text-gray-800 dark:text-gray-100 border-b border-black/10 dark:border-gray-900/50 bg-gray-50 dark:bg-[#444654]">
<div class="text-base gap-4 md:gap-6 md:max-w-2xl lg:max-w-2xl xl:max-w-3xl p-4 md:py-6 flex lg:px-0 m-auto">
<div class="relative flex w-[calc(100%-50px)] flex-col gap-1 md:gap-3 lg:w-[calc(100%-115px)]">
<div class="flex flex-grow flex-col gap-3">
<div class="min-h-[20px] flex flex-col items-start gap-4 whitespace-pre-wrap">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<p>The swiftlet is a small bird known for its valuable nests that are used in the luxury food and beverage industry. However, despite the well-known economic value of swiftlet nests, there is still much to learn about the bird itself. For example, what do swiftlets like to eat and why is their saliva so expensive? What is the lifespan of a swiftlet and what are the signs of their presence? Are swiftlet nests halal and what makes them so special? This article will answer these questions and provide more information about swiftlets, which are often regarded as mysterious and exotic animals.</p>
<p><strong>What Do Swiftlets Like to Eat?</strong></p>
<p>Swiftlets are known as birds that are very selective about their food. They only eat certain types of food that allow them to produce saliva to build their nests. Some of the preferred foods of swiftlets include flies, moths, and other flying insects. In addition, they also consume nectar from flowers that have high sugar content.</p>
<p>As the swiftlet nest industry has developed, some farmers have even tried to provide additional food to increase the production of saliva from swiftlets. Some of the additional foods given include seafood such as anchovies and small shrimp, honey, and certain herbal ingredients.</p>
<p><strong>What Makes Swiftlets Expensive?</strong></p>
<p>Swiftlets are known as birds with high economic value due to their nests being used as food and medicine. One reason why swiftlets are highly valued is because they can only make their nests in certain places such as caves and buildings with specific environmental conditions.</p>
<p>In addition, swiftlets have a relatively short lifespan of around 4-5 years. This makes it difficult to raise swiftlets and makes them even more rare and expensive.</p>
<p><strong>What is the Lifespan of a Swiftlet?</strong></p>
<p>Swiftlets have a relatively short lifespan of around 4-5 years. However, swiftlets have a high reproductive rate, which helps to maintain their population stability.</p>
<p>The swiftlet bird usually begins to breed at around 2 years of age. The process of fertilization and egg incubation is done by both swiftlet parents. After hatching, the swiftlet chick is fed with saliva by its parents until it can fly and find food on its own.</p>
<p><strong>Why is Swiftlet Saliva Expensive?</strong></p>
<p>Swiftlet saliva is very expensive because of the specialized attention and high risks involved in its collection. Swiftlet nest keepers have to climb dangerous places such as steep cliffs or dark and dangerous caves.</p>
<p>In addition, the collection of swiftlet nests must be done very carefully to avoid damaging the nests or endangering the swiftlets themselves. This adds to the high risk of swiftlet nest collection and ultimately affects the selling price of its saliva.</p>
<p><strong>Is Swiftlet Nest Halal?</strong></p>
<p>Swiftlet nests are a luxurious food item that is very expensive. In addition, swiftlet nests are often the choice of consumption for people who want to maintain their health. However, many still wonder whether swiftlet nests are halal for consumption by Muslims.</p>
<p>According to the Fatwa of the Indonesian Ulema Council (MUI), swiftlet nests are declared halal for consumption. This is based on the fact that swiftlet nests are formed from swiftlet saliva and do not contain any haram elements.</p>
<p><strong>What Does the Presence of Many Swiftlets Signify?</strong></p>
<p>Swiftlets, besides being famous for their expensive nests, are also believed to bring signs for the owner of the house or the place where the swiftlet nest is located. The presence of many swiftlets that come and nest in a place is believed to bring several signs, including:</p>
<p>A sign of good luck: The abundance of swiftlets that nest in a place is believed to bring good luck to the owner of the house or the place.</p>
<p>A sign of prosperity: The abundance of swiftlets that nest in a place is also believed to bring prosperity to the owner of the house or the place.</p>
<p>A sign of fertility: The presence of swiftlets is also believed to bring a sign of fertility to the owner of the house or the place.</p>
<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p>After reading the above article, it can be concluded that swiftlets are one of the birds that have many benefits, especially in their nests which are considered as high-value food and medicinal ingredients. Swiftlet nests have also been internationally recognized as a nutritious and healthy food item.</p>
<p>In addition, it is important to note that the swiftlet nests produced must be ensured to be halal and clean. Therefore, reliable information and sources need to be sought to ensure that the swiftlet nests consumed are truly halal and do not contain questionable ingredients.</p>
<p>The abundance of swiftlets that approach or build nests in a place can be a good or bad sign depending on local beliefs. However, it is important not to disturb or disrupt swiftlet nests so that the swiftlet population is not disturbed.</p>
<p>If you are interested in learning more about swiftlets and the swiftlet nest industry, you can explore further on the Pelatihan Walet platform. Here, you can learn about starting a swiftlet nest business, identifying types of swiftlets, and how to properly care for swiftlet nests.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/here-are-the-shocking-facts-about-swallows-that-you-need-to-know-what-they-like-to-eat-why-they-are-expensive-and-much-more/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Becoming a Successful Swallow Entrepreneur: Calculating Capital, Profit, and Taxes Accurately!</title>
		<link>/becoming-a-successful-swallow-entrepreneur-calculating-capital-profit-and-taxes-accurately</link>
					<comments>/becoming-a-successful-swallow-entrepreneur-calculating-capital-profit-and-taxes-accurately#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[raulilma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 03:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bisnis Walet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trainingwalet.test/?p=741</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Starting a business in the swiftlet bird industry can be a promising choice due to its potential for high profits. Swiftlet bird nests are one of the commodities that have a high selling price and continue to increase every year. It&#8217;s no wonder that this business is becoming more and more popular. In addition, the &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/becoming-a-successful-swallow-entrepreneur-calculating-capital-profit-and-taxes-accurately"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Becoming a Successful Swallow Entrepreneur: Calculating Capital, Profit, and Taxes Accurately!</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="741" class="elementor elementor-741">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-743e694d elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="743e694d" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6f6103ca" data-id="6f6103ca" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-55dbeb3d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="55dbeb3d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<div>
<div>Starting a business in the swiftlet bird industry can be a promising choice due to its potential for high profits. Swiftlet bird nests are one of the commodities that have a high selling price and continue to increase every year. It&#8217;s no wonder that this business is becoming more and more popular. In addition, the demand for swiftlet bird nests from both domestic and foreign markets continues to increase, opening up opportunities to develop businesses on a larger scale. Besides gaining profits from the sale of swiftlet bird nests, this business can also provide added value in the form of job opportunities for the surrounding community. However, before starting this business, it is important to know the required capital, expected profits, and taxes that need to be paid.</div>
<br />
<div><strong>Swiftlet Bird Business Capital</strong></div>
<br />
<div>The initial capital required to start a swiftlet bird business is quite large because it requires a special place for the swiftlet bird nests. The price of building a swiftlet bird house ranges from IDR 20 million to IDR 50 million, depending on the location and size of the swiftlet bird house being built. In addition, there are also other costs such as feed, care, and nest management that must be incurred. The total capital required to start a swiftlet bird business ranges from IDR 50 million to IDR 100 million.</div>
<br />
<div><strong>Swiftlet Bird Business Profits</strong></div>
<br />
<div>The swiftlet bird business promises significant profits. Based on research, each swiftlet bird can produce one ounce of swiftlet bird nests per year. The price of swiftlet bird nests per ounce varies depending on the quality and sales location. On average, the price of swiftlet bird nests per ounce ranges from IDR 20 million to IDR 30 million. Therefore, the profit that can be obtained from one swiftlet bird per year ranges from IDR 20 million to IDR 30 million. The amount of profit that can be obtained will certainly be greater if there are more swiftlet birds in the swiftlet bird house.</div>
<br />
<div><strong>Swiftlet Bird Nest Taxes</strong></div>
<br />
<div>Swiftlet bird nest taxes are taxes that must be paid every month based on the sales turnover of swiftlet bird nests. This tax is imposed by the government as part of state revenue. The amount of swiftlet bird nest taxes varies depending on the size of the sales turnover. This tax can reach 10% to 30% of sales turnover. Therefore, it is very important to manage the swiftlet bird business well and systematically so that the taxes that need to be paid can be controlled.</div>
<br />
<div><strong>Conclusion</strong></div>
<br />
<div>That&#8217;s the information about the swiftlet bird business, starting from the required capital, expected profits, and swiftlet bird nest taxes that need to be paid. As a swiftlet bird business player, it is important to have sufficient knowledge and skills in managing the business to succeed and gain maximum profits.</div>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/becoming-a-successful-swallow-entrepreneur-calculating-capital-profit-and-taxes-accurately/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here is the Latest Price List of Swiftlet Bird&#8217;s Nest Per Ounce and Per Kilogram from a Trusted Source!</title>
		<link>/here-is-the-latest-price-list-of-swiftlet-birds-nest-per-ounce-and-per-kilogram-from-a-trusted-source</link>
					<comments>/here-is-the-latest-price-list-of-swiftlet-birds-nest-per-ounce-and-per-kilogram-from-a-trusted-source#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[raulilma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 03:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bisnis Walet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sarang Walet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trainingwalet.test/?p=734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Swiftlet nests are one of the commodities that attract the attention of society due to their high market value. This is because of the high demand from domestic and international markets, as well as the difficulty in harvesting them, which requires special techniques and comes with high risks. Swiftlet nests are believed to contain high &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/here-is-the-latest-price-list-of-swiftlet-birds-nest-per-ounce-and-per-kilogram-from-a-trusted-source"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Here is the Latest Price List of Swiftlet Bird&#8217;s Nest Per Ounce and Per Kilogram from a Trusted Source!</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="734" class="elementor elementor-734">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-743e694d elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="743e694d" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6f6103ca" data-id="6f6103ca" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-55dbeb3d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="55dbeb3d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Swiftlet nests are one of the commodities that attract the attention of society due to their high market value. This is because of the high demand from domestic and international markets, as well as the difficulty in harvesting them, which requires special techniques and comes with high risks. Swiftlet nests are believed to contain high nutritional value and are believed to have health benefits for humans, which is why many people are interested in consuming or trading them.</p>
<p>The price of swiftlet nests is quite high, so it is not surprising that many people are interested in finding information about their prices. However, one of the problems that often arises is the lack of information about the price of swiftlet nests. How much does one ons or one kilogram of swiftlet nest cost? The price of swiftlet nests can vary depending on several factors, such as the quality of the nest, the origin of the nest, and also the market conditions at the time.</p>
<p>According to some sources, the price of swiftlet nests can reach millions of rupiahs per kilogram. The price varies depending on the quality and origin of the nest. Swiftlet nests from Indonesia are usually cheaper than those from countries such as Thailand or Malaysia. The price of swiftlet nests can also differ depending on the market conditions at the time. Based on information obtained from the e-commerce site Bukalapak, the price of swiftlet nests in Indonesia currently ranges from IDR 20 million to IDR 25 million per kilogram. However, the price can vary depending on the quality, size, and origin of the swiftlet nest. Meanwhile, according to the news site Tribunnews, the price of swiftlet nests in the world market can reach USD 3,000 to USD 6,000 per kilogram.</p>
<p>As for the price of swiftlet nests per ons, according to some sources, the price can range from tens of thousands to hundreds of thousands of rupiahs. Based on information from the Alibaba website, the price of swiftlet nests per ons varies from USD 50 (IDR 763,400.00) to USD 600 (IDR 9,160,800.00), depending on the quality and size of the nest.</p>
<p>However, the price of swiftlet nests is indeed very high. Therefore, before buying swiftlet nests, it is important to do research and choose high-quality nests at a reasonable price. It is also important to buy swiftlet nests from trustworthy sellers with a good reputation in the market. That way, you can ensure that you get high-quality swiftlet nests at a fair price.</p>
<p>Overall, the price of swiftlet nests can vary greatly depending on several factors such as the quality and origin of the nest. Despite their high price, swiftlet nests are still a commodity that is in high demand due to their high nutritional value and health benefits. Therefore, it is important to do research and buy swiftlet nests from trustworthy sellers to get high-quality nests at a reasonable price.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/here-is-the-latest-price-list-of-swiftlet-birds-nest-per-ounce-and-per-kilogram-from-a-trusted-source/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exploring Careers in Swiftlet Farming: An Interesting Perspective</title>
		<link>/exploring-careers-in-swiftlet-farming-an-interesting-perspective</link>
					<comments>/exploring-careers-in-swiftlet-farming-an-interesting-perspective#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[raulilma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 02:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Karir Walet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trainingwalet.test/?p=709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Industri walet menjadi salah satu bisnis yang semakin diminati oleh banyak orang. Sarang burung walet yang dihasilkan oleh burung walet sangatlah mahal di pasaran karena banyak diminati oleh konsumen di seluruh dunia, terutama di Asia. Dalam industri ini, setiap perusahaan walet membutuhkan berbagai jenis pekerjaan, mulai dari pemanen, pengolahan, hingga pemasaran produk. Sistem kerja di &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/exploring-careers-in-swiftlet-farming-an-interesting-perspective"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Exploring Careers in Swiftlet Farming: An Interesting Perspective</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="709" class="elementor elementor-709">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-743e694d elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="743e694d" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6f6103ca" data-id="6f6103ca" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-55dbeb3d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="55dbeb3d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Industri walet menjadi salah satu bisnis yang semakin diminati oleh banyak orang. Sarang burung walet yang dihasilkan oleh burung walet sangatlah mahal di pasaran karena banyak diminati oleh konsumen di seluruh dunia, terutama di Asia. Dalam industri ini, setiap perusahaan walet membutuhkan berbagai jenis pekerjaan, mulai dari pemanen, pengolahan, hingga pemasaran produk.</p>
<p>Sistem kerja di perusahaan walet cukup unik, terutama dalam hal pengolahan sarang burung walet. Karena setiap langkah pengolahan harus dilakukan secara manual, maka perusahaan walet memerlukan tenaga kerja yang cukup banyak dan terlatih. Mulai dari membersihkan sarang, mengambil sarang yang sudah jadi, hingga mengolah sarang menjadi berbagai jenis produk yang siap dipasarkan.</p>
<p>Meskipun pekerjaan di perusahaan walet cukup menantang dan memerlukan keterampilan khusus, namun gaji yang ditawarkan bisa dibilang cukup menggiurkan. Sebagai contoh, pemanen sarang burung walet bisa mendapatkan gaji harian antara 200 ribu hingga 1 juta rupiah tergantung pada jumlah sarang yang berhasil dikumpulkan. Sedangkan untuk pekerjaan pengolahan sarang burung walet, gaji yang ditawarkan bervariasi mulai dari 1,5 juta hingga 6 juta rupiah per bulan.</p>
<p>Banyak perusahaan yang bergerak di bidang ini dan menawarkan berbagai jenis pekerjaan. Namun, sebelum memilih bekerja di perusahaan walet, ada baiknya mengetahui lebih lanjut mengenai jenis pekerjaan yang tersedia dan gaji yang ditawarkan. Berikut uraiannya:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Pemanen Sarang Walet</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Pekerjaan sebagai pemanen sarang walet menjadi salah satu pekerjaan yang paling banyak dibutuhkan di perusahaan walet. Tugas utama seorang pemanen adalah memanen sarang yang sudah dihasilkan oleh burung walet. Pemanen sarang walet biasanya bekerja di malam hari karena itulah saat burung walet kembali ke sarangnya.</p>
<p>Gaji yang ditawarkan untuk pekerjaan ini bervariasi tergantung pada daerah dan perusahaan tempat bekerja. Namun, rata-rata gaji yang diterima oleh pemanen sarang walet adalah sekitar Rp 2 juta hingga Rp 4 juta per bulan.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Peternak Burung Walet</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Pekerjaan sebagai peternak burung walet juga menjadi salah satu pilihan bagi mereka yang ingin bekerja di perusahaan walet. Peternak burung walet bertanggung jawab untuk merawat burung walet mulai dari memberikan pakan, memelihara kandang, hingga mengobati burung yang sakit.</p>
<p>Gaji yang ditawarkan untuk pekerjaan ini juga bervariasi tergantung pada daerah dan perusahaan tempat bekerja. Namun, rata-rata gaji yang diterima oleh peternak burung walet adalah sekitar Rp 3 juta hingga Rp 5 juta per bulan.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Teknisi Sistem Ventilasi</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Sistem ventilasi merupakan salah satu hal yang sangat penting dalam bisnis sarang burung walet. Teknisi sistem ventilasi bertanggung jawab untuk memastikan ventilasi di dalam kandang burung walet berfungsi dengan baik. Mereka juga harus memperbaiki dan memelihara sistem ventilasi agar burung walet tetap merasa nyaman di dalam kandang.</p>
<p>Gaji yang ditawarkan untuk pekerjaan ini juga bervariasi tergantung pada daerah dan perusahaan tempat bekerja. Namun, rata-rata gaji yang diterima oleh teknisi sistem ventilasi adalah sekitar Rp 3 juta hingga Rp 6 juta per bulan.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><strong>Marketing dan Penjualan Sarang Walet</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Pekerjaan sebagai marketing dan penjualan sarang walet juga menjadi salah satu pilihan bagi mereka yang ingin bekerja di perusahaan walet. Tugas utama seorang marketing dan penjualan sarang walet adalah memasarkan dan menjual sarang burung walet yang sudah dihasilkan oleh perusahaan.</p>
<p>Gaji yang ditawarkan untuk pekerjaan ini juga bervariasi tergantung pada daerah dan perusahaan tempat bekerja. Namun, rata-rata gaji yang diterima oleh marketing dan penjualan sarang walet adalah sekitar Rp 4 juta hingga Rp 8 juta per bulan.</p>
<p>Dalam keseluruhan, perusahaan walet menawarkan berbagai jenis pekerjaan yang menarik dan menantang. Bagi mereka yang tertarik untuk bekerja di industri yang unik dan berbeda, perusahaan walet mungkin merupakan pilihan yang menarik. Namun, pekerjaan di perusahaan walet juga membutuhkan keahlian dan pengetahuan khusus, serta ketangkasan dan ketelitian dalam melaksanakan tugasnya. Oleh karena itu, bagi mereka yang ingin mengejar karir di perusahaan walet, perlu mempersiapkan diri dan memperoleh pengetahuan yang dibutuhkan untuk berhasil dalam pekerjaan ini.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/exploring-careers-in-swiftlet-farming-an-interesting-perspective/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Markaswalet Menggelar Seminar dan Pelatihan Budidaya Sarang Burung Walet di Kota Balikpapan (Online)</title>
		<link>/markaswalet-menggelar-seminar-dan-pelatihan-budidaya-sarang-burung-walet-di-kota-balikpapan-online.html</link>
					<comments>/markaswalet-menggelar-seminar-dan-pelatihan-budidaya-sarang-burung-walet-di-kota-balikpapan-online.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[raulilma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 06:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Balikpapan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seminar Training]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trainingwalet.test/?p=702</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pada akhir Maret 2020, Indonesia diserang oleh pandemi Covid-19 dan daerah Kalimantan Timur, termasuk Kota Balikpapan, mulai bersiap menghadapinya. Meskipun tim Markaswalet telah merencanakan kegiatan pelatihan di wilayah tersebut, namun akibat kondisi yang tidak memungkinkan, pelatihan tersebut terpaksa dilakukan secara online. Tim Markaswalet tetap optimis dapat mengadakan kegiatan pelatihan secara offline di wilayah tersebut pada &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/markaswalet-menggelar-seminar-dan-pelatihan-budidaya-sarang-burung-walet-di-kota-balikpapan-online.html"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Markaswalet Menggelar Seminar dan Pelatihan Budidaya Sarang Burung Walet di Kota Balikpapan (Online)</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="702" class="elementor elementor-702">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-743e694d elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="743e694d" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6f6103ca" data-id="6f6103ca" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-55dbeb3d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="55dbeb3d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Pada akhir Maret 2020, Indonesia diserang oleh pandemi Covid-19 dan daerah Kalimantan Timur, termasuk Kota Balikpapan, mulai bersiap menghadapinya. Meskipun tim Markaswalet telah merencanakan kegiatan pelatihan di wilayah tersebut, namun akibat kondisi yang tidak memungkinkan, pelatihan tersebut terpaksa dilakukan secara online. Tim Markaswalet tetap optimis dapat mengadakan kegiatan pelatihan secara offline di wilayah tersebut pada tahun berikutnya.</p>
<p>Kalimantan Timur memiliki kekayaan alam berupa hasil sarang burung walet yang melimpah. Daerah ini menjadi pusat pengepul sarang burung walet di Indonesia. Kualitas sarang burung walet di daerah Kalimantan Timur cenderung rata dan bervariasi. Gedung walet di daerah perkotaan biasanya berukuran lebih besar namun lebih tipis dibandingkan dengan daerah lain.</p>
<p>Kegiatan pelatihan online yang diadakan oleh tim Markaswalet hanya fokus pada proses budidaya walet dan pengembangan Gedung walet. Para peserta mengumpulkan denah Gedung walet masing-masing untuk dapat dilakukan bedah denah tata ruang dan tata suara selama kegiatan seminar online. Istilah-istilah seperti void, lubang antar ruangan, lubang antar lantai, sekat gantung, sekat gergaji, sekat Tarik, dan roofing area dalam perwaletan juga dibahas. Kestabilan suhu dan kelembaban pada Gedung walet menjadi faktor penting untuk menghasilkan sarang burung walet yang optimal.</p>
<p>Ada beberapa metode yang dapat dilakukan untuk menjaga kestabilan suhu dan kelembaban di Gedung walet. Salah satunya adalah melapisi bagian luar Gedung dengan acian atau a plus yang terstandar dan menggunakan sterofoam pada bagian dalam Gedung untuk menjaga agar tidak terpapar sinar matahari berlebihan. Selain itu, pemasangan jaring-jaring hitam pada posisi luar Gedung juga dapat membantu memperkecil rambatan sinar matahari. Baskom air yang diberikan pada setiap meter persegi dan bata merah yang ditempatkan di dalam baskom juga dapat membantu menjaga kelembaban di dalam Gedung walet.</p>
<p>Selama kegiatan pelatihan, para peserta merasa kewalahan dengan suhu dan kelembaban yang tidak terjaga pada Gedung walet mereka. Rata-rata Gedung walet peserta pelatihan memiliki skema los atau tidak memiliki sekat khusus, sehingga ruangan inap atau nesting room pada Gedung walet dipenuhi oleh cahaya yang banyak. Hal ini seharusnya dihindari karena burung walet sangat nyaman tinggal di lingkungan yang gelap. Oleh karena itu, penting untuk menjaga kestabilan suhu dan kelembaban serta menerapkan skema yang tepat pada Gedung walet agar dapat menghasilkan sarang burung walet yang berkualitas.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/markaswalet-menggelar-seminar-dan-pelatihan-budidaya-sarang-burung-walet-di-kota-balikpapan-online.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Markaswalet Menggelar Seminar dan Pelatihan Budidaya Sarang Burung Walet di Kota Mataram</title>
		<link>/markaswalet-menggelar-seminar-dan-pelatihan-budidaya-sarang-burung-walet-di-kota-mataram.html</link>
					<comments>/markaswalet-menggelar-seminar-dan-pelatihan-budidaya-sarang-burung-walet-di-kota-mataram.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[raulilma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 05:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mataram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Offline Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seminar Training]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trainingwalet.test/?p=697</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mataram adalah ibu kota provinsi Nusa Tenggara Barat yang terletak di bagian barat Pulau Lombok yang terkenal dengan destinasi wisatanya yang eksotis. Namun, kondisi ekosistem dan alam NTB juga mendukung proses budidaya sarang burung walet. Sumber air yang melimpah serta banyaknya hutan dan kebun menyediakan lingkungan yang ideal bagi burung walet untuk mencari makan. Dompu, &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/markaswalet-menggelar-seminar-dan-pelatihan-budidaya-sarang-burung-walet-di-kota-mataram.html"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Markaswalet Menggelar Seminar dan Pelatihan Budidaya Sarang Burung Walet di Kota Mataram</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="697" class="elementor elementor-697">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-743e694d elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="743e694d" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6f6103ca" data-id="6f6103ca" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-55dbeb3d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="55dbeb3d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p><p>Mataram adalah ibu kota provinsi Nusa Tenggara Barat yang terletak di bagian barat Pulau Lombok yang terkenal dengan destinasi wisatanya yang eksotis. Namun, kondisi ekosistem dan alam NTB juga mendukung proses budidaya sarang burung walet. Sumber air yang melimpah serta banyaknya hutan dan kebun menyediakan lingkungan yang ideal bagi burung walet untuk mencari makan. Dompu, Bima, Lombok Timur, Lombok Barat, dan Lombok Tengah adalah beberapa lokasi yang menjadi sentra budidaya burung walet di provinsi ini sehingga menjadi daerah favorit para petani burung walet untuk membangun rumah waletnya.</p><p>Dengan demikian, destinasi selanjutnya yang dipilih tim Markaswalet adalah wilayah NTB. Dengan potensi pengembangan yang sangat besar dan industri wisata yang berkembang pesat, sarang burung walet yang bersih dapat dipasarkan langsung kepada wisatawan yang berkunjung ke pulau cantik ini. Acara ini akan berlangsung selama dua hari, pada hari Sabtu dan Minggu, tanggal 7 dan 8 Maret 2020, di Favehotel Mataram. Selain teknik beternak burung walet, Markaswalet juga akan memberikan pelatihan khusus tentang pengolahan dan pembersihan sarang burung walet agar para petani burung walet memperoleh keterampilan yang diperlukan untuk profesinya.</p><p>Kegiatan di Mataram pada Sabtu ini meliputi dasar-dasar beternak burung walet, antara lain struktur rumah walet, material yang digunakan dalam konstruksinya, terminologi yang digunakan dalam penataan ruangan, dan suara-suara yang dibutuhkan untuk memikat burung walet. Peserta juga akan belajar tentang teknik khusus memasang rumah walet. Di penghujung hari, setiap peserta akan mendapat kesempatan untuk menjelaskan kesulitan apa saja yang mereka temui di rumah walet mereka. Misalnya, beberapa petani mungkin mengalami masalah dengan distribusi sarang burung walet yang tidak merata di berbagai lantai rumah mereka, yang seringkali disebabkan oleh struktur suara yang tidak jelas.</p><p>Di hari kedua, setiap peserta akan mendapatkan kesempatan untuk praktik membersihkan dan mengolah sarang burung walet dalam sebuah workshop. Setiap peserta akan diberikan sarang burung walet yang kotor dengan bulunya dan diajarkan cara membersihkannya dengan benar. Menurut peraturan, sarang burung walet yang tidak bersih tidak dapat diekspor karena mengandung nitrit yang tinggi, yang harus di bawah 30 ppm untuk diekspor. Proses pembersihan sarang burung walet harus dilakukan dengan hati-hati dan higienis. Alat-alat penting termasuk pinset, tisu, lembaran plastik, semangkuk air, kaca pembesar, lampu, dan meja. Alat khusus seperti cetakan sarang burung walet juga diperlukan, antara lain mangkok, piring, dan cetakan miring. Selain itu, ruangan untuk membuat sarang burung walet harus memiliki AC dan dehumidifier untuk menghilangkan kelembapan berlebih.</p><p>Selama acara di Lombok atau Mataram, tim Markaswalet juga berkesempatan untuk melakukan survei lapangan di dekat pantai Tanjung Luar di Lombok Timur. Kawasan ini merupakan rumah bagi banyak burung walet, terbukti dari lima rumah burung walet yang sudah berpuluh-puluh tahun menghasilkan sarang burung walet yang melimpah. Dari segi kualitas, Lombok menghasilkan sarang burung walet dengan warna nasi putih, nasi merah, krem, merah, dan kuning.</p><p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/markaswalet-menggelar-seminar-dan-pelatihan-budidaya-sarang-burung-walet-di-kota-mataram.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Markaswalet Menggelar Seminar dan Pelatihan Budidaya Sarang Burung Walet di Kota Makassar</title>
		<link>/markaswalet-menggelar-seminar-pelatihan-budidaya-sarang-burung-walet-di-kota-makassar.html</link>
					<comments>/markaswalet-menggelar-seminar-pelatihan-budidaya-sarang-burung-walet-di-kota-makassar.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[raulilma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 03:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Makassar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Offline Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seminar Training]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trainingwalet.test/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1" class="elementor elementor-1">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-743e694d elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="743e694d" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6f6103ca" data-id="6f6103ca" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-55dbeb3d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="55dbeb3d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Markaswalet baru-baru ini mengadakan program pelatihan budidaya burung walet di Makassar, Sulawesi pada Februari 2020. Inisiatif ini diselenggarakan bersama oleh Markaswalet dan asosiasi terkemuka di Sulawesi, Markas Vitron Indonesia. Acara tersebut dihadiri mayoritas petani burung walet dari Sulawesi Selatan, antara lain dari Sinjai, Bulukumba, Wajo, Sengkang, Pare-pare, dan Siwa. Pesertanya pun beragam, mulai dari yang sudah lama menggeluti bisnis hingga pendatang baru. Materi pelatihan dirancang agar mudah dipahami oleh semua peserta, terlepas dari tingkat pengalaman mereka dalam beternak burung walet.</p>
<p>Program pelatihan berlangsung selama dua hari pada tanggal 1 dan 2 Februari 2020 di Hotel Amaris Makassar yang terletak di pusat kota. Tujuan dari program ini adalah untuk memberikan pemahaman yang komprehensif kepada petani burung walet tentang budidaya burung walet. Banyak petani burung walet yang tidak mengetahui seluk-beluk budidaya burung walet, yang dapat menyebabkan pengambilan keputusan yang buruk saat membangun rumah burung walet. Akibatnya, hanya 30% rumah walet di Sulawesi yang berhasil, sisanya masih dalam tahap perkembangan populasi.</p>
<p>Sulawesi memiliki karakter yang unik, dengan rumah walet tersebar di setiap wilayah, mulai dari selatan, utara, tengah, barat, hingga tenggara. Sengkang dan Wajo yang terletak di wilayah Sulawesi Selatan memiliki sejarah budidaya burung walet terpanjang di pulau ini. Namun, mayoritas sarang burung walet berkualitas tinggi ditemukan di Sulawesi Tengah (Kota Palu dan Kabupaten Poso) dan Sulawesi Barat (Kabupaten Mamuju), ditandai dengan sarang berwarna putih seperti kapas dan sarang ringan berbulu.</p>
<p>Pemetaan lokasi rumah burung walet di setiap daerah memudahkan pemerintah dalam melakukan sensus rumah burung walet, yang pada gilirannya memberikan edukasi kepada petani burung walet untuk mengembangkan budidaya burung walet sesuai dengan update akademik. Saat ini terlihat kesenjangan antara petani burung walet dengan pemerintah, karena kedua belah pihak merasa tidak saling membutuhkan. Oleh karena itu, Markaswalet berharap dengan adanya pelatihan dan seminar budidaya burung walet, seluruh elemen dapat bersinergi untuk memajukan budidaya burung walet di Indonesia.</p>
<p>Sebagian besar peserta di Makassar menceritakan bahwa perkembangan peternakan walet di rumah mereka lambat. Ada yang membangun rumah walet berukuran besar, seperti tingkat 6 x 12 x 7, sementara yang lain membangun rumah walet yang lebih kecil, seperti tingkat 4 x 8 x 2. Masalah umum yang dihadapi oleh para petani burung walet adalah penataan ruangan yang buruk dan tingkat kebisingan di rumah burung walet mereka. Melihat foto-foto rumah walet yang dibagikan oleh para peserta, terlihat bahwa banyak dari mereka yang membangun rumah walet tanpa perencanaan yang jelas, seperti rencana tata ruang, rencana kebisingan, dan rencana anggaran.</p>
<p>Salah satu peserta memiliki panen yang cukup sukses, tetapi pertumbuhannya mandek selama tiga tahun terakhir. Sebaliknya, banyak petani burung walet di Sinjai yang berhasil meningkatkan hasil panennya secara signifikan. Kemungkinan penyebab stagnasi pertumbuhan peserta adalah sistem pemanenan yang tidak tepat, yang cenderung mendukung pemanenan paksa, menyebabkan ketidaknyamanan pada burung walet muda, menyebabkan mereka melarikan diri dari rumah walet. Markaswalet berencana untuk membahas semua teknik budidaya burung walet ini secara komprehensif di situs webnya.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/markaswalet-menggelar-seminar-pelatihan-budidaya-sarang-burung-walet-di-kota-makassar.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
