<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sarang Walet &#8211; Pelatihan Walet</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/sarang-walet/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>The Best Swallow Cultivation Seminar and Training Provider in Indonesia</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 15:08:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/cropped-icon-training-walet-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Sarang Walet &#8211; Pelatihan Walet</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Here is the Latest Price List of Swiftlet Bird&#8217;s Nest Per Ounce and Per Kilogram from a Trusted Source!</title>
		<link>/here-is-the-latest-price-list-of-swiftlet-birds-nest-per-ounce-and-per-kilogram-from-a-trusted-source.html</link>
					<comments>/here-is-the-latest-price-list-of-swiftlet-birds-nest-per-ounce-and-per-kilogram-from-a-trusted-source.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[raulilma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 03:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bisnis Walet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sarang Walet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trainingwalet.test/?p=734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Edible birdnests are one of the commodities that attract the attention of society due to their high market value. This is because of the high demand from domestic and international markets, as well as the difficulty in harvesting them, which requires special techniques and comes with high risks. Edible birdnests are believed to contain high &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/here-is-the-latest-price-list-of-swiftlet-birds-nest-per-ounce-and-per-kilogram-from-a-trusted-source.html"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Here is the Latest Price List of Swiftlet Bird&#8217;s Nest Per Ounce and Per Kilogram from a Trusted Source!</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="734" class="elementor elementor-734">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-743e694d elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="743e694d" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6f6103ca" data-id="6f6103ca" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-55dbeb3d elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="55dbeb3d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<style>/*! elementor - v3.11.2 - 22-02-2023 */
.elementor-widget-text-editor.elementor-drop-cap-view-stacked .elementor-drop-cap{background-color:#818a91;color:#fff}.elementor-widget-text-editor.elementor-drop-cap-view-framed .elementor-drop-cap{color:#818a91;border:3px solid;background-color:transparent}.elementor-widget-text-editor:not(.elementor-drop-cap-view-default) .elementor-drop-cap{margin-top:8px}.elementor-widget-text-editor:not(.elementor-drop-cap-view-default) .elementor-drop-cap-letter{width:1em;height:1em}.elementor-widget-text-editor .elementor-drop-cap{float:left;text-align:center;line-height:1;font-size:50px}.elementor-widget-text-editor .elementor-drop-cap-letter{display:inline-block}</style>				<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Edible birdnests are one of the commodities that attract the attention of society due to their high market value. This is because of the high demand from domestic and international markets, as well as the difficulty in harvesting them, which requires special techniques and comes with high risks. Edible birdnests are believed to contain high nutritional value and are believed to have health benefits for humans, which is why many people are interested in consuming or trading them.</p>
<p>The price of edible birdnests is quite high, so it is not surprising that many people are interested in finding information about their prices. However, one of the problems that often arises is the lack of information about the price of edible birdnests. How much does one ons or one kilogram of edible birdnest cost? The price of edible birdnests can vary depending on several factors, such as the quality of the nest, the origin of the nest, and also the market conditions at the time.</p>
<p>According to some sources, the price of edible birdnests can reach millions of rupiahs per kilogram. The price varies depending on the quality and origin of the nest. Edible birdnests from Indonesia are usually cheaper than those from countries such as Thailand or Malaysia. The price of edible birdnests can also differ depending on the market conditions at the time. Based on information obtained from the e-commerce site Bukalapak, the price of edible birdnests in Indonesia currently ranges from IDR 20 million to IDR 25 million per kilogram. However, the price can vary depending on the quality, size, and origin of the edible birdnest. Meanwhile, according to the news site Tribunnews, the price of edible birdnests in the world market can reach USD 3,000 to USD 6,000 per kilogram.</p>
<p>As for the price of edible birdnests per ons, according to some sources, the price can range from tens of thousands to hundreds of thousands of rupiahs. Based on information from the Alibaba website, the price of edible birdnests per ons varies from USD 50 (IDR 763,400.00) to USD 600 (IDR 9,160,800.00), depending on the quality and size of the nest.</p>
<p>However, the price of edible birdnests is indeed very high. Therefore, before buying edible birdnests, it is important to do research and choose high-quality nests at a reasonable price. It is also important to buy edible birdnests from trustworthy sellers with a good reputation in the market. That way, you can ensure that you get high-quality edible birdnests at a fair price.</p>
<p>Overall, the price of edible birdnests can vary greatly depending on several factors such as the quality and origin of the nest. Despite their high price, edible birdnests are still a commodity that is in high demand due to their high nutritional value and health benefits. Therefore, it is important to do research and buy edible birdnests from trustworthy sellers to get high-quality nests at a reasonable price.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/here-is-the-latest-price-list-of-swiftlet-birds-nest-per-ounce-and-per-kilogram-from-a-trusted-source.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
